<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<!-- Secsrch Tue May 11 11:07:46 2004 -->

<report version="1.0">
  <reportinfo>
    <version>2.39</version>
    <logdatestart></logdatestart>
    <logdateend></logdateend>
    <title>Security Log File Analysis</title>
    <analysisstart> Tue May 11 11:07:46 2004</analysisstart>
    <inputfiles>
      <file>/var/tmp/30290ex000916.log</file>
    </inputfiles>
    <outputfile>&amp;STDOUT</outputfile>
    <execstart>Tue May 11 11:07:46 2004</execstart>
    <execstop>Tue May 11 11:07:46 2004</execstop>
    <rowsanalysed>1299</rowsanalysed>
    <rowsanalysedpersec>1299</rowsanalysedpersec>
    <nripaddr></nripaddr>
    <perf>1299</perf>
    <nameresoff>1</nameresoff>
  </reportinfo>
  <logformats>
    <rec>
      <format>Field definitions</format>
      <nrfound>1</nrfound>
    </rec>
    <rec>
      <format>MS-IIS Extended</format>
      <nrfound>1295</nrfound>
    </rec>
    <rec>
      <format>Ignored Comments</format>
      <nrfound>3</nrfound>
    </rec>
  </logformats>
  <hitsperhour>
    <title>Hits per hour</title>
    <desc>This shows the number of Hits per hour. Any sudden drops or increases in traffic can be due to web pounders stealing bandwidth, or an effective Denial of Service.</desc>
    <rec>
      <hour>0</hour>
      <hits>0</hits>
    </rec>
    <rec>
      <hour>1</hour>
      <hits>0</hits>
    </rec>
    <rec>
      <hour>2</hour>
      <hits>0</hits>
    </rec>
    <rec>
      <hour>3</hour>
      <hits>0</hits>
    </rec>
    <rec>
      <hour>4</hour>
      <hits>0</hits>
    </rec>
    <rec>
      <hour>5</hour>
      <hits>0</hits>
    </rec>
    <rec>
      <hour>6</hour>
      <hits>0</hits>
    </rec>
    <rec>
      <hour>7</hour>
      <hits>0</hits>
    </rec>
    <rec>
      <hour>8</hour>
      <hits>0</hits>
    </rec>
    <rec>
      <hour>9</hour>
      <hits>0</hits>
    </rec>
    <rec>
      <hour>10</hour>
      <hits>0</hits>
    </rec>
    <rec>
      <hour>11</hour>
      <hits>0</hits>
    </rec>
    <rec>
      <hour>12</hour>
      <hits>0</hits>
    </rec>
    <rec>
      <hour>13</hour>
      <hits>0</hits>
    </rec>
    <rec>
      <hour>14</hour>
      <hits>0</hits>
    </rec>
    <rec>
      <hour>15</hour>
      <hits>0</hits>
    </rec>
    <rec>
      <hour>16</hour>
      <hits>0</hits>
    </rec>
    <rec>
      <hour>17</hour>
      <hits>0</hits>
    </rec>
    <rec>
      <hour>18</hour>
      <hits>0</hits>
    </rec>
    <rec>
      <hour>19</hour>
      <hits>0</hits>
    </rec>
    <rec>
      <hour>20</hour>
      <hits>0</hits>
    </rec>
    <rec>
      <hour>21</hour>
      <hits>0</hits>
    </rec>
    <rec>
      <hour>22</hour>
      <hits>0</hits>
    </rec>
    <rec>
      <hour>23</hour>
      <hits>0</hits>
    </rec>
  </hitsperhour>
  <dangerousfiles total="0" uniq="0">
    <title>Successful attempts to retrieve Dangerous files</title>
    <desc>This could indicate successful attempts to retrieve sensitive files, or possibly execute system commands in the server.</desc>
  </dangerousfiles>
  <unauthorized total="0" uniq="0">
    <title>Users who have accessed protected page</title>
    <desc>This shows all users who have accessed password protected pages. Users whi repeatedly access the same page could indicate password brute force attempts.</desc>
  </unauthorized>
  <logged_in_users total="0" uniq="0">
    <title>Logged in users</title>
    <desc>Lists all users who have successfully logged in. Verify that the users are valid.</desc>
  </logged_in_users>
  <logged_in_users_per_ip total="0" uniq="0">
    <title>Logged in user per IP-address</title>
    <desc>Shows the source IP-addresses of successful logins. Make sure all addresses are valid or can be derived.</desc>
  </logged_in_users_per_ip>
  <statuscodes total="0" uniq="0">
    <title>Statuscodes</title>
    <desc>Shows all Statuscodes. If 404's are missing, this probably indicates a fualty error-page. Excessive 4xx and 5xx codes can indicate problems that need further investigation.</desc>
  </statuscodes>
  <httpmethods total="0" uniq="0">
    <title>List of HTTP methods found</title>
    <desc>Shows all attempted Methods. GET and POST are most common and normal. Others can indicate reconnossaince attempts, or manipulation attempts, however there are many Methods which are legitimate, depending on server and configuration.</desc>
  </httpmethods>
  <httpversions total="0" uniq="0">
    <title>Count of HTTP-verssions</title>
    <desc>There are basically two (or maybe three) HTTP versions: HTTP/1.0, HTTP/1.1, HTTP/0.9. Anything else is either a faulty browser or reconnossaince / manipulation attempts. Keep an eye on addresses generating invalid HTTP versions.</desc>
  </httpversions>
  <illegalhttp total="0" uniq="0">
    <title>Invalid HTTP-versions</title>
    <desc>This list all requests done without a valid HTTP version. This could indicate attempts to connect via telnet or other tcp based mechanism, usually indicating reconnosaince. Keep an eye on addresses in this list.</desc>
  </illegalhttp>
  <tophitters total="0" uniq="0">
    <title>List of Top Hitters</title>
    <desc>This list shows the addresses requesting the most pages (hits). Each hit uses resources - cpu and bandwidth. Top IP's in this list can indicate anything from a valid interested user, to a spider crawling your site looking for security holes. Or someone asking repetitive querys to your database. Keep an eye on the top IP's.</desc>
  </tophitters>
  <errors4xx total="0" uniq="0">
    <title>Access attempts generating 4xx errors</title>
    <desc>This list indicates the top requests for nonexistent pages. The tops on this list either indicate faulty links in the sites HTML code, or you are being hit by malicious worms.</desc>
  </errors4xx>
  <top4xxerrorsperip total="0" uniq="0">
    <title>Top 4xx errors per IP</title>
    <desc>This list shows the addresses requesting the most nonexistent pages (hits). Each request for a nonexistent page can mean one or more ofseveral things\: 1) Someone is actively looking for known security holes on yoursite. 2) There are faulty links in your HTML code. 3) You are being hit by malicious selfpropagating worms. 4) Someone is performing reconnossaince of your site. And failing. Bottom line\? Top hitters on this list could actively be looking for security holes - monitor their IP's</desc>
  </top4xxerrorsperip>
  <top4xxerrorsperipurl total="0" uniq="0">
    <title>Top 4xx errors per IP and URL</title>
    <desc>Is any single IP hammering your site for a non-existent page? Possible Denial-of-Service attempt, or faulty site configuration.</desc>
  </top4xxerrorsperipurl>
  <top_5xx_errors_per_ip total="0" uniq="0">
    <title>Top 5xx errors per IP</title>
    <desc>Errors generated here are on the server. This could either be manipulation attempts, or excessive database access. Or just a misconfiguration of the web server.</desc>
  </top_5xx_errors_per_ip>
  <top_5xx_errors_per_url total="0" uniq="0">
    <title>Top 5xx errors per URL</title>
    <desc>Errors generated here are on the server. This couldeither be manipulation attempts, or excessive database access. Or just a misconfiguration of the web server. If the same URL is causing the errors, this might indicate the source of the problem. Or possibly a security breach.</desc>
  </top_5xx_errors_per_url>
  <top_5xx_errors_per_ip_url total="0" uniq="0">
    <title>Top 5xx errors per IP and URL</title>
    <desc>Is any single IP using a specific URL to wreak havoc on your web server?</desc>
  </top_5xx_errors_per_ip_url>
  <url_with_binary_data total="0" uniq="0">
    <title>URL's containing binary data</title>
    <desc>This is a no-no. Anything listed here should not happenunder normal circumstances, since binary data is not allowed in a URL. It should always be encoded in some way. Entries gere could indicate attempts to cause buffer overflows and security breaches. There is a possible false positive with some obscure browsers sending odd binary data, but it is not common. Check these IPs!</desc>
  </url_with_binary_data>
  <topreferers total="0" uniq="0">
    <title>Top Referers</title>
    <desc>This is mostly for reference, but if your server is vulnerable, someone might have put a link to it on their site. And you will then see where they are coming from (i.e. refered to).</desc>
  </topreferers>
  <top_blank_ref total="0" uniq="0">
    <title>Top Blank Referers</title>
    <desc>This could indicate information-harvesters fetching pages through an automated tool. It would also show users coming through bookmarked pages.</desc>
  </top_blank_ref>
  <topbrowsers total="0" uniq="0">
    <title>Top Browsers used</title>
    <desc>This is mostly for reference. The most common browsers are listed in their various formats. However, there are tools which use non-common  brosers. Use of such can be indicative of reconnossaince of the site. Be observant of the top and bottom entries in this list.</desc>
  </topbrowsers>
  <cookiemanip total="0" uniq="0">
    <title>Suspected Cookie Manipulation</title>
    <desc>This could inidicate attempted session hijacking (unlikely, but serious), or users coming via a non-ip session aware proxy (likely, and not so serious).</desc>
  </cookiemanip>
  <xss_per_ip total="0" uniq="0">
    <title>Cross Site Scripting Attempts per IP</title>
    <desc>Anything listed here could indicate Cross Site Scripting attempts. If successfull, they could allow stealing of your users credentials, and thus alleviating unauthorized access. Successfull attempts listed here mustbe examined further.</desc>
  </xss_per_ip>
  <subdirlist total="0" uniq="0">
    <title>Subdirectory Listing Attempts</title>
    <desc>This indicates reconnosaince buy attempting to list subdirectories of the site. The perpetrator is presumably looking for misconfigureddefault pages or trying to view source code.</desc>
  </subdirlist>
  <unsuc_subdir_ip total="0" uniq="0">
    <title>Unsuccessful Subdir attempts per IP</title>
    <desc>If the Top IP's generate errors on many subdirectories, it is a probable attempted (and possibly succeeded) reconnossaince sweep.</desc>
  </unsuc_subdir_ip>
  <formmanip total="0" uniq="0">
    <title>List suspected FORM manipulation</title>
    <desc></desc>
  </formmanip>
  <locateproxy total="0" uniq="0">
    <title>Attempts to locate Proxy</title>
    <desc>This indicates attempts to locate and possibly use the site to stage further attacks. If the proxy attempts are successful, the site could be used to relay spam or participate in illegitimate activities.</desc>
  </locateproxy>
  <longurlattempt total="0" uniq="0">
    <title>Exceedingly Long URLs</title>
    <desc>These could indicate attempts to locate and use Buffer Overflows to compromise the Web Server, and shoud be considererd as serious attempts to breach Security.</desc>
  </longurlattempt>
</report>
